<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Web Book</title>
    <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Web Book</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang with no Googling</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/golang_with_no_googling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/golang_with_no_googling/</guid>
      <description>I spent a good amount of time learning Golang (Go, but since using two letters in any form of a search usually is an exercise in futility). My goal was fairly simple, I wanted to display some system statistics via HTTP by reading them directly from /proc. I saw that Golang had a module in the standard library call &amp;quot;syscall&amp;quot; and I decided that it might be fun to give that a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GnuTLS and ed25519</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/gnutls_ed25519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/gnutls_ed25519/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very excited that GNUTLS has support for ed25519 keys, these keys are faster, smaller, and more secure than RSA keys. I found this out from a developer&amp;rsquo;s blog while doing research and messing around with CA&amp;rsquo;s in December. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m writing this is that GNUTLS 3.6 has been made available in Fedora 28, therefore can all use this. Additionally and perhaps more importantly we gain the the ability to use TLS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An End of Disk Issues?</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/end_of_disk_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/end_of_disk_issues/</guid>
      <description>I have a workstation that I have built, it contains a multi-disk Large Form Factor ZFS array. There have been multiple posts in the past about some of my disk related problems that I&amp;rsquo;ve handled, you should be able to find them with a &amp;lsquo;zfs&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;disk&amp;rsquo; tag. Well I had several issues, that I hope should be calming down; going back to January, where I decided to move from 4x3TB RAID-Z (software RAID 5) to 4x4TB 7200RPM RAID 10 setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SELF 2018</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/self-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/self-2018/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed SouthEast LinuxFest this year, probably more this year than I did last year. Mostly because I made a point of being more outgoing and interacting with more people. Last year I attended I had tried talking to a few people but didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a good feel for things, and volunteered for the FSF booth and tried to take the Ham radio exam. This year I attended many presentations, had an opportunity to go to a Birds Of a Feather meeting on containers put on by Michael at RedHat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume Blogging</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/resume-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/resume-blogging/</guid>
      <description>After a few issues that almost perfectly lined up to steal momentum I&amp;rsquo;m going to resume blogging. If you follow this (I doubt many were/are), I apologize for the lack of updates. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to briefly run down some of the events that lead to the large (almost year delay): The Prior Events  Before SouthEast Linux Fest my Wife&amp;rsquo;s mother very unexpectedly died. After SELF I had some motivation and tried to look into interesting topics, generally Software Defined Radio (I liked the LimeSDR) and followed some crypto currency investigation which lead to Zcash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL Video</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/openssl-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/openssl-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;document&#34;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After having to generate a SHA1 certifcate and other people on my team did not understand the cert process, I make a video on it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urxvt_vs_eterm</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/urxvt_vs_eterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/urxvt_vs_eterm/</guid>
      <description>====== urxvt vs Eterm ====== So I was trying different terminals so that I can keep on terminal just for a screencast sessions. I want to keep screencasting clean and partitioned. Additionally I have admitted to myself (now everyone else) that I need to know more about profiling the system, I got [http://www.brendangregg.com/books.html](Breddan Gregg&amp;rsquo;s book ) on system performance, so far its very through. One complaint is that as a Solaris guy and even regarding many of his Linux presentations and writings is that he really favors dtrace, for obvious reasons; its a fantastic tracing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Matthew Weekend</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/hurricane_matthew_weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/hurricane_matthew_weekend/</guid>
      <description>As rain falls from Hurricane Matthew, I can&amp;rsquo;t split wood or I have started to work on some items, and have recorded various thoughts.
I started to look at the failure of the btrfs volume, this truly appears that the failure was not hardware related; instead it is just corrupt checksums. I ran two SMART tests on all of my hard drives, none of them (I paid particular attention to the drives mentioned that were corrupt) had failed any tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>options-vs-arguments-vs-parameters</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/options-vs-arguments-vs-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/options-vs-arguments-vs-parameters/</guid>
      <description>====== options, arguments, or parameters ======
Where I am currently employed there has been, in my opinion, an over application of the term &amp;ldquo;parameter&amp;rdquo;. Or at least from where I have been in the past. I have always thought that for example:
example -x test.txt -x would be a switch, and the option after -x, test.txt, would be argument. But it seems here or recently we apply the term parameter to everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>standardization</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/standardization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/standardization/</guid>
      <description>====== Standardization ====== I am sure many of us have seen the xkcd comic &amp;ldquo;Standrads&amp;quot;, if not check it out, its kinda funny. I have been thinking about the debate and later burden that we seem to impose on ourselves through well intended standardization. This came around when there was a discussion at my full time employer about standardizing a spaces around the text and brackets only_if {node.fqdn.upcase =~ &#39;PROD&#39;} compared to only_if { node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>powershell_linux_debut</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/powershell_linux_debut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/powershell_linux_debut/</guid>
      <description>Powershell Linux debut I began to experiment with Powershell. I feel that Microsoft has to follow through on showing the community that it meant what it said, that Microsoft Loves Linux. Perhaps I can lump myself into that group too, because I remember the October Document, and the utter frustration in trying to get Linux to work in a mostly Windows environment. I think Microsoft senses that the game is changing, and is changing with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/modern-marvels-engineering-disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/modern-marvels-engineering-disasters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;document&#34;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After watching Modern Marvels Engineering Disasters series I reflect on our profession and our &amp;quot;disasters&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAID5 btrfs total failure and subsequent abandonment</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/btrfs_total_failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/btrfs_total_failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;document&#34;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;btrfs RAID 5 fails entirely and takes my data with it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bash tips 1</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/bash_tips1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/bash_tips1/</guid>
      <description>BASH tips So I read a comment on Hacker News about ctrl+o and and the comment (and subsequent comments) made it sound as though it was this ultra helpful trick. Well I had a bit of difficulty finding what and how to use, perhaps its because I&amp;rsquo;m a bit stupid. So here is how it works, you type a command (I found it works best when you use ctrl+r then press ctrl+o) press ctrl+o instead of enter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pyenv</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/pyenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/pyenv/</guid>
      <description>Version Managers I have been enjoying the idea of version managers for interpreted languages like Ruby, Python and even NodeJS. Python likes to advocate using virtualenv, which works very well when interacting and writing the code. However when interacting with automation like Ansible or Chef this becomes difficult since you have to source the shell scripts to install a given version.
Some might argue that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a need to have one of these version managers, and as you might guess I disagree with that, and advocate for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>white_spaces_can_be_dangerous</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/white_spaces_can_be_dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/white_spaces_can_be_dangerous/</guid>
      <description>====== White spaces can be dangerous ====== When I was some go I noticed that it refused to compile due to a white space:
&#39;&amp;rsquo; ./go-test-router.go:17: invalid identifier character U+2502 ./go-test-router.go:17: syntax error: unexpected name, expecting } &#39;&amp;rsquo;
I have noticed this first with Microsoft Windows formatting of white spaces and new lines. This is also true Word quotes. This was due to the fact that we had to put documentation on sharepoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tiddlywiki_entry_everyday_for_30_days</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/tiddlywiki_entry_everyday_for_30_days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/tiddlywiki_entry_everyday_for_30_days/</guid>
      <description>====== Tiddlywiki entry everyday for 30 days ======
I&amp;rsquo;m going to make it a goal to make a tiddlywiki entry every day for 30 days. This will be in effort to help form a habit. Here is my plan, add items to track quick ideas like Million dollar ideas, things to research, plans for the house, programming/learning notes. Really Tiddlywiki should be quick and dirty, I want this dokuwiki to be more mature, organized, especially since it&amp;rsquo;s versioned with git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>x2go or FreeNX</title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/x2go_or_freenx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/x2go_or_freenx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;document&#34;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After working on a Bohdi ticket I express fondness for Neatx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/btrfs_scrub_fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/btrfs_scrub_fail/</guid>
      <description>title: btrfs Scrub Fail date: 2016-05-05 category: devops tags:
 linux btrfs slug: btrfs_srub_fail description: I experience unrecoverable error on btrfs RAID 5, ignoring previous claims of instability   btrfs scrub fail I wrote this earlier on a internal corporate blog (Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s Confluence), but I don&amp;rsquo;t think many read it, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give out any corporate information, but since I wrote it on &amp;ldquo;company time&amp;rdquo; I figured I should put it there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/emacs/</guid>
      <description>title: Emacs date: 2016-09-18 category: linux tags:
 emacs slug: give_emacs_another_try description: I revisit emacs, and try to use it   emacs Those that know me, know that I preach the use of vi as an editor. Reason being as those who know me might be able to recite: vi is everywhere and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be installed, its very powerful for its size, some jobs demand it! That fact was mentioned to me by someone at Phoenix Linux Users Group meeting, which was call CAT (Chat About Technology; lets go eat CAT, it was a bad joke, but we went with it) someone stated that some GE jobs require the use knowledge of vi, sure enough I went to [http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/tls_in_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondor6c.github.io/posts/tls_in_practice/</guid>
      <description>Trust TLS What is trust? It really is the common name for the measure of authenticity, mainly testing the location you are trying to connect to. The standard by which something is verified to be genuine. The verification of the client is really more of authentication, user/client. The two are very similar, an authentic which is probably why they both share the same root name, authentikos greek meaning approximately original, primary one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>